AAYUSH GIRI

Dhanbad, Jharkhand · +91 7661835084

aayushgiri1234@gmail.com · LinkedIn · GitHub · Portfolio

I am a Blockchain Researcher and Developer. I am currently focused on building accessible, human-centred products on blockchain protocols. I have previously contributed to some great Open-Source Projects centred around Ethereum. I am an individual with a proven track record in adapting to multiple technology domains with a serious affinity toward emerging technologies.

EDUCATION

DEC 2020 - JUL 2024

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY, INDIAN INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY (ISM)

- Four-year Electronics and Communication Engineering degree. Currently among the top performing students of the branch, with a CGPA of 8.15
- Some relevant technical skills gained through academics are C lang, C++, Python, Object Oriented Programming, Computational Finance, Microcontroller architecture and basic intel x86 assembly.

APR 2017 – JUN 2019

HIGH-SCHOOL GRADUATION, FIITJEE JUNIOR COLLEGE

- Major in Physics, Math and Chemistry with graduation score of 94%.

EXPERIENCE

JUL 2022 - PRESENT

CLUB FOUNDER, BLOCKCHAIN STUDENT LEARN CLUB

- Blockchain researcher spreading Web3 awareness
- Speaker for a Solidity workshop, teaching EVM and CLI
- Developed an application to share public key encrypted files to user
- Conducted several development tests for club students on regular basis
- Technical support for coding competition and hackathons

JUN 2022 – AUG 2022

SUMMER RESEARCH INTERNSHIP, INDIAN INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY (ISM)

Conducted this research work under the mentorship of Professor Dr. Ramesh Dharavath. The internship covered different blockchain topics and also made me gain knowledge in federated learning.

- Worked on model designing and implementing a system that solves the known trust problem in the existing COVID-19 vaccine supply chain.
- Developed smart contracts in solidity to model the supply chain system for a trust less supply chain system.

SKILLS

- React.js & Next.js
- Truffle Suite
- Paper writing (IEEE format)
- Interplanetary file storage (IPFS)
- Alchemy
- Adaptability

ACTIVITIES

- Among top teams for XMTP protocol labs at ETH-GLOBAL (HackFS) and won prize of \$1000
- Got selected for open-source contribution at Social Summer of Code (SSOC) 2022.
- Semi -Finalist in EUREKA 2021 Asia's largest business model competition
- Top 10 in HACKFEST 2021 among 300+ participants.
- Constantly learning smart contract development past 11 months.
- Volunteered for teaching basic Solidity coding for high-school students.
- Certifications:
 - o Blockchain Basics University of Buffalo (Coursera)
 - o Blockchain Foundation & Use Cases Consensys Academy (Coursera)
 - o Smart Contracts University of Buffalo (Coursera)
 - o Ethereum Blockchain Development with Solidity (Udemy)
 - o Decentralized Applications University of Buffalo (Coursera)
 - o HackerRank certified in Problem Solving and Python.

PROJECTS

- 1. **Drop-Chain** (Decentralized File Storage System)
 - Created a DApp which allows users to start storing their encrypted files.
 - o It utilizes the power of decentralized storage to store files securely, which are encrypted by an AES encrypting algorithm before being uploaded.
 - The file's CID is stored in a smart contract where only the owner can access them, and the
 encryption key is also available there, heavily encrypted.
- 2. **Messaging for Lenster** (messaging integration in decentralised social media)
 - Built the messaging feature for the decentralized social media platform Lenster which is built upon the lens protocol.
 - Integrated messaging feature using the XMTP protocol by creating a chatting environment enabled with Real-time push notifications.
 - Increased the convenience of chatting using Lenster handle Id instead of using wallet addresses.
- 3. **Crypt** (Send cryptocurrency across the world)
 - Developed a platform to send assets to provided wallet addresses by integrating Metamask
 - Productionized this service to automatically push transactions upon Etherscan which can be viewed